Using your second brain:

Note: While most of the information in this document is relevant, you can find out more updated information by loading the "Help Brain" on the same menu that got you this.


You started off with a blank node with some welcome information.

You can edit the title and description of the node while they are visible by clicking and editing the text boxes that display them. You may wonder why, if I designed this program to work with Fudge and other roleplaying games, I didn't include some kind of functionality to support traits or statistics within those games. The reason is simple: Fudge is played in too many ways, all intercompatible, with too many variations, that making a program compatible with them all is effectively impossible. (At least for a teacher programming in the evenings.) The only thing that all the widely varied Fudge GMs shared was...well...text.

You can change the type designation of the present node by clicking on the type-indicator to the right of the title. (This is initially showing a yellow question mark and the word Undefined.) You probably want to define some common types of node right away. Use the Type menu to make new types and to define icons to associate with those types. (Examples might be places, NPCs, PCs, items, Monsters..etc.) 

You can create new nodes by hitting the "Spawn" button on the lower right-hand panel. This creates a new node and links it to the node you were just viewing. You are then switched to that node and it displays for editing. Note that the type of this new node is determined by the Default type selector in the type menu. So if you want to create a lot of villages quickly, you could set the default type to "Village" (or place, or settlement or whatever _you_ think is appropriate) and then create many in a row. 

You can "de-link" nodes by viewing on of the nodes and selecting the one you wish to de-link from on the link list. Then hit the "De-link" button and the link will disappear. The node will still be there, but the mutual references will be removed. 

You can view any node on the link-list at any time by double-clicking it, or by selecting it on the list and clicking the "Goto" button. You can zip right into a particular node (even if its not linked to the one you're presently viewing) by selecting the NodeWeb>>Search Web menu item. This brings up a list of all the nodes in the campaign web. You can select one for viewing.

You can create links between existing nodes by viewing one of the prospective partners and clicking the "Add Link" button. This will bring up a list of all the available nodes, from which you can select one to create a new link to. By default, this will creat a two-way link between the nodes, and they will appear on each others' link lists.

The File menu contains all the standard operations. These operations (presently) work only for the entire campaign web. You can also export to XML. This may be useful for formating and presenting data, but the interlinking nature of the nodes doesn't fit the "tree" definition of XML very well and tends to give databases fits. Exporting to HTML will create one long webpage, with a standard node output for each node, but with hyperlinks between linked nodes. When exporting to HTML, the nodes are presently output in the order created. (Which is why its good to start a web with an introductory node.)

It is possible to create nodes that become orphans. That is, all the links to them are removed. This makes the node isolated and "impossible" to reach from other nodes. This could lead to duplicate or lost information. Therefore, you can use NodeWeb>>Find Lost menu item to find these nodes and link form them to other nodes.