The Types for the nodes are composed of three items.

1) a name for that type of Node
2) an icon for that type of Node
3) an URL for that type of icon (for reference purposes)

During saves, nodes only save the URL reference for their icons. They are generated again upon reading. This means that moving your file from machine to machine might lose the proper icons. This should not cause the program to malfunction.

Icons can be restored (or changed) for a given type of node by selecting the Types>>Change Icon for Type menu item.

Each node merely references the relatively small list of types, they do not store individual types. Hence, if you change a type for one node, you change it for all nodes which share that type. This is why there is no "delete type" feature on the menus. CHOOSE YOUR NODE TYPES CAREFULLY. It is possible to make two node types functionally Identical. This shouldn't affect the operation of the program in any significant way. If you find that you have too many types of node, do not fear. You can combine types by making the names of both types identical. (two families of "Killer" nodes)

NOTE!: Two node types with the same name will converge after a file is saved and opened. It is not easily predictable which icon will be preserved.

The icons I used for nodes are simple, small Gif files. I recommend the same. I suppose you could use jpg or bmp, but gif has that nifty transparency feature. Note that those are the only options at present, as they are natively supported by JAVA.

Unused types are *not* presently saved with a file. So if you have a type that just isn't used, it will vanish when you save the file. (Of course, It can be recreated easily using the appropriate menu item.)

