This Program is designed to help Game Masters keep their heads, and to allow easy access to information in play and to allow them add to that information easily during play.

Basically, you can think of a campaign or adventure as a web of ideas and thoughts. You can define the nature of each "node" in the web as its "type". You can define your own types, and little icons to go with them.

Each Node has a title, description, type, and a list of other nodes that it is linked to. You can view these linked nodes on the right side of the frame. You can go to those nodes by clicking on them. More details about actually using the program are available in the other help file.

I was inspired to write this program after folks on the Fudge mailing list kept mentioning how its hard to keep writing adventures/stories in a campaign where a combat wouldn't take up most of the session. It occured to me that the format most of us use for writing campaign information isn't the most efficient. This is what my brain wanted, so I whipped it up. I kept the size as small as possible so that folks might use it on smaller (read: handheld) machines.

If you use the program and have any helpful comments to convey, please drop me an e-mail at
 jughrin @ yahoo*dot*com.

However, this program is distributed under the terms of the GPL, so you are free to make modifications on your own! So don't think I'm holding you back.

Hope you enjoy!

John Ughrin